Guide to the Semans family papers, 1878-2008 and undated RL.01167
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- James H. and Mary D.B.T. Semans Family Papers, 1925-1991
  - Pictures Series
    - Upright Boxes
      - Semans, James H.: (Box 86)
        - 1950s-1980s (Box 86)
        - Oak Grove Cemetery, Uniontown, Pa. ( Semans family graves), 1980s (Box 86)
        - Uniontown Semans relatives, 1950s-1980s (Box 86)
      - Semans, Mary D.B.T.:
        - ca. 1920-1980s, 9 folders (Box 86)
        - ca. 1926-1930,with Biddle, Nicholas B.D. (Box 86)
        - 1932,with Schelling, Ernest (Box 86)
        - 1938,with Trent, Josiah Charles (Box 86)
        - 1940,with Trent, Josiah Charles and daughter, Mary (Box 86)
        - 1945,undated, with Trent, Josiah Charles (Box 86)
        - 1940s-1950s, with daughters (Box 86)
        - 1940s, with Trent, Josiah Charles and daughters (Box 86)
        - 1930s, Duke University (Box 86)
        - ca. 1920-1929, Palm Beach, Fla., 3 folders (Box 86)
      - Semans, Mary D.B.T. and James H.: (Box 87)
        - Events:
          - Arts, 1971-1988 (Box 87)
          - The Duke Endowment, 1979,undated (Box 87)
          - Duke Homestead Dedication, 1968 (Box 87)
          - Duke University:
            - undated (2 folders) (unidentified) (Box 87)
            - Commencement, 1983, 1986, 2 folders (Box 87)
          - Durham City/County, 1950s (Box 87)
          - Elon College, 1965 (Box 87)
          - Executive Mansion Fine Arts Committee, undated (Box 87)
          - Guilford College, Greensboro, N.C., 1968 (Box 87)
          - Mary Duke Biddle Foundation, 1979 (Box 87)
          - National Conference of Christians and Jews--Award, 1969 (Box 87)
          - North Carolina Museum of Art, 1964, 1967 (Box 87)
          - North Carolina (State of), 1976-1982,undated, 2 folders (Box 87)
          - Yale University School of Music, 1981 (Box 87)
          - Unidentified, undated
            - Portraits, 1977 (Box 87)
            - Snapshots, 1950s-1980s (Box 87)
      - Semans family:
        - ca. 1950s-1980s, 2 folders (Box 87)
        - Children, ca. 1940s-1956, undated, 4 folders (Box 87)
      - Trent/Semans Family Christmas cards: (Box 88)
        - 1938-1988, 11 folders (Box 88)
        - 1940-1965,prints of photographs used as Christmas cards (Box 88)
      - Trent, Josiah Charles:
        - 1920s-1940s, 2 folders (Box 88)
        - Medical school/internship/residency, 1930s-1940s (Box 88)
      - Trent, Mary Simpson, 1940s-1950s (Box 88)
      - Trent family, 1940s-1980s (Box 88)
      - Buildings and grounds: (Box 89)
        - Duke family mausoleum, Maplewood Cemetery, Durham, N.C., ca. 1960 (Box 89)
        - Duke Farms, Somerville, N.J., undated (Box 89)
        - Four Acres, Durham, N.C., undated (Box 89)
        - Four Acres: butler's pantry and bathroom, 1961 (Box 114)
        - Four Acres: dining room, 1961 (Box 114)
        - Four Acres: drawing room, 1961; 2 folders (Box 114)
        - Four Acres: exterior, 1961; 2 folders (Box 114)
        - Four Acres: library, 1961 (Box 114)
        - Four Acres: reception hall, 1961; 2 folders (Box 114)
        - Four Acres: staircase, 1961; 3 folders (Box 114)
        - Four Acres: upstairs hallway, Sarah P. Duke wedding anniversary gowns, 1961 (Box 114)
        - Houses, miscellaneous, undated (Box 89)
        - Linden Court [Irvington-on-the-Hudson], Tarrytown, N.Y., 1956,undated, 2 folders (Box 89)
        - Palm Beach, Fla., 1920s-1930s (Box 89)
        - Pinecrest, Durham, N.C., 1960 (Box 89)
        - Pinecrest and Les Terrasses, Durham, N.C., undated (Box 89)
        - 1009 5th Avenue, New York, N.Y. 1929, 1990,undated (Box 89)
        - Sarmiento, Palm Beach, Fla., ca. 1920s-1930s (Box 89)
        - Sepulchral Chapel, Duke University, undated (Box 89)
      - Naval Ships: U.S. Battleships, ca. 1930s-1940s (Box 89)
      - People:
        - Duke University:
          - Medical school (students/staff), 1941-1950s (Box 89)
          - Vigil for Martin Luther King, 1968 (Box 89)
          - Related pictures, undated (Box 89)
        - Men:
          - Identified, 1941, 1984,undated (Box 89)
          - Unidentified, undated (Box 89)
          - In Palm Beach, Fla., 1930s (unidentified) (Box 89)
        - Women:
          - Identified, undated (Box 89)
          - Unidentified, 1900- 1940s, undated, 2 folders (Box 89)
        - Miscellaneous people:
          - Identified, 1930s-1980s, 2 folders (Box 89)
          - Unidentified, 1931, 1954,undated (Box 89)
          - Political, 1960s, undated (Box 89)
          - Recreational scenes, 1920s (unidentified) (Box 89)
      - Travel photographs:
        - India, Japan (Yagi family), American West, 1910s-1930s (Box 89)
        - 1953-1986, 4 folders (Box 89)
    - Flat Boxes
      - Biddle, Anthony J. Drexel: (Box 90)
        - Drawings, 1916-1954 (Box 90)
        - 1930s, 2 folders (Box 90)
        - ca. 1944-1945,World War II (Box 90)
        - With Biddle, Mary Duke, mid-1910s-1930s (Box 90)
        - With son, Biddle, Nicholas Benjamin Duke, 1920-1930s (Box 90)
      - Biddle, Cordelia Rundell Bradley, ca. 1920 (Box 90)
      - Biddle, Mary Duke:
        - ca. 1920-1939, 2 folders (Box 90)
        - With Biddle, Anthony J. Drexel, ca. 1920s (Box 90)
        - With Biddle, Anthony J. Drexel and children, 1921-1926 (Box 90)
      - Biddle, Nicholas Benjamin Duke, ca. 1920s-1932 (Box 90)
      - Duke, Anthony Drexel, ca. 1920s (Box 90)
      - Duke, Benjamin Newton and Duke, Sarah Pearson Angier:
        - ca. 1915-1920,with Duke, Angier Buchanan and his family (Box 90)
        - ca. 1920-1925,with grandchildren Mary and Nicholas Biddle (Box 90)
      - Duke, James Buchanan, 1900s, undated (Box 90)
      - Duke, Washington, 1900s (portrait) (Box 90)
      - Jones, Mary Duke Trent, 1940 (Box 91)
      - Semans, Mary D.B.T.:
        - ca. 1920s-1936, 4 folders (Box 91)
        - Alone; with Biddle, Nicholas B.D., ca. 1932-1935 (Box 91)
        - Pencil drawing, 1937 (Box 91)
        - School plays, 1930s (Box 91)
        - With daughter, Mary, 1940 (Box 91)
        - With Trent, Josiah Charles and daughters, 1943 (Box 91)
        - With Trent, Josiah Charles, 1938 (Box 91)
      - Semans family, children, undated (unidentified) (Box 91)
      - Family Christmas cards, transparencies and prints, 1978-1981, 2 folders (Box 91)
      - Trent, Josiah Charles, 1920-1940s (Box 91)
      - Buildings and grounds:
        - Duke family mausoleum, Maplewood Cemetery, Durham, N.C., ca. 1900 (Box 91)
        - Duke University. Etchings by Louis Orr, 1930s (Box 91)
        - Four Acres (?), undated (Box 91)
        - Sarmiento, Palm Beach, Fla., 1920s-1930s (Box 91)
      - People: (Box 92)
        - Men (unidentified), undated (Box 92)
        - Palm Beach, Fla., 1930s (unidentified) (Box 92)
        - Women (unidentified), 1902 (Box 92)
        - Miscellaneous:
          - 1930s, unidentified children (Box 92)
          - Identified, n.d (Box 92)
      - The Duke Endowment Presentation Album, 40th Anniversary, 1964 (Box 92)
      - (Fragile material): (Box 93)
        - Mary Duke Biddle, 1920s (Box 93)
        - Angier Buchanan Duke, 1880s (Box 93)
        - Benjamin N. Duke and Sarah P. Duke, 1880s (Box 93)
        - Benjamin N. Duke, ca. 1900 (Box 93)
      - Negatives: (Box 94)
        - Balls/Parties, 1950s (Box 94)
        - Biddle, Anthony J. Drexel, ca. 1915-1930s (Box 94)
        - Biddle, Mary Duke and Biddle, Anthony J. Drexel, and daughter, 1920 (Box 94)
        - Duke, Benjamin N. and Duke, Sarah P., undated (Box 94)
        - Duke family mausoleum, undated (Box 94)
        - Duke University Medical Center, Josiah C. Trent Library, Room Dedication, 1956 (Box 94)
        - Christmas cards, 1949-1968, 2 folders (Box 94)
        - Christmas holiday, 1956-1957 (Box 94)
        - Harris, Sally Elizabeth Trent, 1960,undated, 2 folders (Box 94)
        - House: Miscellaneous, 1950s, undated (Box 94)
        - Jones, Mary Duke Trent, 1941-1959, 2 folders (Box 94)
        - Semans, J.H. and M.D.B.T., 1970s (Box 94)
        - Semans, Mary D.B.T. with daughters, ca. 1949-1950 (Box 94)
        - Semans/Trent family, ca. 1947-1948 (Box 94)
        - Semans family and Elizabeth Gotham, 1954-1955 (Box 94)
        - Semans family, ca. 1955-1960, June, 10 folders (Box 94)
        - Semans, Mary D.B.T.:
          - Before 1953,undated, 2 folders (Box 94)
          - And James H. Semans, ca. 1954-1955 (Box 94)
        - Travel: Miscellaneous, 1935-1960,undated (Box 94)
        - Trent, Josiah C., undated (Box 94)
        - Trent boat, undated (Box 94)
        - Miscellaneous, 1950s, 1980s (Box 94)
  - Miscellaneous Series:
    - Audio-Visual Materials
      - Audio Tapes: (Box 95)
        - Cassette: Memoirs, Semans, Mary D.B.T., 1977, Jan. 15 (Box 95)
        - 5 inch reels:
          - Newcomer: Duke Makes a Difference, 1964, Jan. 16 (Box 95)
          - Rehabilitation in Jerusalem, Semans, Mary D.B.T., 1965, Aug. 8 (Box 95)
          - John Riley, Sept. 16(?) (Box 95)
        - 7 inch reels:
          - Breakfast, 1975[?] Unused [label difficult to read] (Box 95)
          - Music (?), undated (partial reel) (Box 95)
          - Wedding of Rebecca Trent and John Kirkland, 1965, June 26 (Box 95)
          - National Conference of Christians and Jews Awards Dinner, 1969, Sept. 9(2 tapes) (Box 95)
      - Audio Tapes: (Box 96)
        - 7 inch reel:
          - Mr. Riley #2 Nova Scotia, undated (Box 96)
          - Target: Artistic Oasis at Winston-Salem, undated (2 tapes) (Box 96)
      - Motion picture film, 16 mm:
        - Siena:
          - 1968(7 inch reel) (Box 96)
          - Fanfani: alla Accademia Chigiana, undated (5 inch reel) (Box 96)
          - Unlabeled, undated (3 inch reel) (Box 96)
    - Other Materials
      - Address Books: Semans family, undated, 3 folders (Box 97)
      - Awards, 1951-1987, 4 folders (Box 97)
      - Beta Rho Sorority minutes, 1938, Apr. (Box 97)
      - Births: Announcements/certificates, 1914-1962 (Box 97)
      - Calendars, 1952-1957, 5 folders (Box 97)
      - Calendars, 1957-1970, 11 folders (Box 98)
      - Calendars, 1972-1985, 8 folders (Box 99)
      - Calendars, 1973-1975(3 books) (Box 100)
      - Calendars, 1976-1978(3 books) (Box 101)
      - Calendars, 1979-1981(3 books) (Box 102)
      - Clippings, 1915-1990,undated, 13 folders (Box 103)
      - Lichen Flora: Parmelia Seman Siana, 1980 (Box 104)
      - Piano Recitals ( Mary D.B.T. Semans), 1930-1934 (Box 104)
      - School reports:
        - ( Miss Hewitt's School), 1928-1935;( Woman's College, Duke University), 1936 (Box 104)
        - Semans, Elizabeth Gotham, 1968-1980,undated (Box 104)
        - Semans, James D.B.T., 1965-1976 (Box 104)
        - Semans, Jenny Lillian, 1966-1972,undated (Box 104)
        - Trent, Barbara Biddle, 1949-1964,undated (Box 104)
        - Trent, Mary Duke, 1951-1957 (Box 104)
        - Trent, Rebecca Grey, 1955-1964 (Box 104)
        - Trent, Sally Elizabeth, 1956-1959 (Box 104)
        - Trent, Josiah C., 1929-1970,undated (Box 104)
        - Trent, Sally Elizabeth, Diary, 1958 (trip to Europe) (Box 104)
      - Weddings: (Box 105)
        - 1938-1953, 2 folders (Box 105)
        - Announcements, Semans family, 1961-1987 (Box 105)
- Elizabeth Lucina Gotham Family Papers, 1902-1968; 1920s-1930s
  The Elizabeth Lucina Gotham family papers are useful for the study of women's history, particularly that of women trained as baby nurses in the early twentieth century. The papers span the years 1902 to 1968, with the bulk occurring in the 1920s. They include correspondence, pictures, a few genealogical items and clippings. Most of the Correspondence Series consists of letters from Miss Gotham's family and women friends. Many of the latter are evangelistic in nature and include letters mailed from a missionary station in Honduras.
  A significant amount of correspondence to Elizabeth Gotham from Mary D.B.T. Semans and her family, which documents their close relationships, is in the James H. and Mary D.B.T. Semans Family Papers Correspondence Series. It dates from about 1938 to 1941 and then is scattered throughout the 1950s and 1960s.
  The Pictures Series includes photographs of Gotham family members, portraits of nurses and nurses in baby hospitals, and towns in the state of New York.
  - Correspondence Series
    - 1902-1968, 5 folders (Box 106)
    - Clippings, 1918-1971,undated (Box 107)
  - Pictures Series
    - ca. 1880s-1960s, 5 folders (Box 107)
    - ca. 1900-1940 (women) (Box 107)
    - ca. 1900-1920 (men) (Box 107)
    - ca. 1900-1940s (weddings, births, groups, miscellaneous) (Box 107)
    - ca. 1900-1964 (mostly children) (Box 107)
    - 1930s-1950s Trent/Semans family (Box 107)
    - ca. 1920s-1967 (Duke and Biddle family members) (Box 107)
    - 1880s-1930s (miscellaneous buildings) (Box 107)
    - ca. 1905, nursing school or hospital, Brooklyn, N.Y. (Box 107)
    - undated (Box 107)
- Oversize Materials
  - Mary Duke Biddle Family Papers
    - Scrapbook Series
      - Angier B. Duke, B.N. Duke, 1923-1931 (Oversize-box 108)
      - Family, early 1930s (Oversize-box 108)
      - Biddle divorce, 1930-1931 (Oversize-box 108)
  - James H. Semans Family Papers
    - Pictures Series
      - Francis Marion Semans and family, 1902, 1938,undated (Box 112)
    - Miscellaneous Series
      - Awards, 1932-1943 (Oversize-box 108)
  - James H. and Mary D.B.T. Semans Family Papers
    - Subject Files Series
      - Duke Homestead, 1968 (Oversize-box 108)
      - Durham, N.C.:
        - Community Chest speech given by Mary D.B.T. Semans, 1952 (Oversize-box 108)
        - Durham City Council:
          - Voting tallies, 1950s (Oversize-box 108)
          - Campaign poster, 1950s (Oversize-box 108)
    - Pictures Series
      - Biddle, Anthony Joseph Drexel, 1914-1920 (Oversize-box 109)
      - Biddle, Mary Duke, 1910-1930s (Oversize-box 109)
      - Duke, Angier Buchanan:
        - ca. 1880-1923 (Oversize-box 109)
        - With sister, Mary Lillian Duke, 1890 (Oversize-box 109)
      - Duke, Benjamin Newton, ca. 1890-1926 (Oversize-box 109)
      - Duke, Doris, 1920,undated (Oversize-box 109)
      - Duke, Sarah Pearson Angier:
        - alone, undated (Oversize-box 109)
        - funeral, 1936 (Oversize-box 109)
      - Duke, Washington, 1870-1880, 2 folders (Oversize-box 109)
      - Duke/Biddle family, Durham, N.C., 1910-1920 (Oversize-box 109)
      - Semans, Mary D.B.T (Oversize-box 110)
        - ca. 1920-1933, 3 folders (Oversize-box 110)
        - With Biddle, Nicholas Benjamin Duke, ca. 1930s (Oversize-box 110)
      - Semans, Mary D.B.T. and James H., Events: The Duke Endowment, 1973 (Oversize-box 110)
      - Semans family: Children, undated (Oversize-box 110)
      - Trent, Josiah Charles, 1930 (Oversize-box 110)
      - Buildings and Grounds:
        - Duke Homestead, 1920,undated (Oversize-box 110)
        - Durham Homes, Inc., Unity Village, ca. 1970 (Oversize-box 110)
        - Newport, R.I.: Chetwold (Storrs Wells/Astor Home), undated (Oversize-box 110)
        - Palm Beach, Fla.:
          - Bath and Tennis Club, ca. 1920 (Oversize-box 110)
          - Everglades Club(?), ca. 1920 (Oversize-box 110)
          - Sarmiento, ca. 1920 (Oversize-box 110)
        - 1009 Fifth Avenue, New York, N.Y., undated (Oversize-box 110)
      - Miscellaneous (identified), 1960,undated (Oversize-box 110)
      - Mary Duke Biddle Foundation/The Duke Endowment: Publicity Shots, ca. 1970 (Oversize-box 110)
      - Pictures-fragile (shelved out-of-sequence) (Oversize-box 111)
      - Biddle, Mary Duke: (Box 112)
        - 1915 (wedding) (Box 112)
        - ca. 1930s (Box 112)
      - Semans, James H. and Mary D.B.T., 1953 (wedding) (Box 112)
      - Semans family still nitrate negatives, undated; 0.4 Linear Feet (Box 113)
    - Miscellaneous Series
      - Audio-Visual Materials
        - Phonograph record, Mary D.B.T. Semans, ca. 1931,undated (Oversize-box 108)
      - Other Materials
        - Awards, 1947-1982 (Box 112)
        - Diploma for Mary Lillian Duke, 1897 (Box 112)
        - Floor Plans and Plats for properties in N.Y. and N.C., 1948-1975 (Oversize-folder 1)
        - Paper Dolls, 1920s (Box 112)
- Films and video, 1914-1968
  Original film media are closed to use; viewing copies may need to be made for access to content. Please contact the Rubenstein Library before coming to use this material.
  - Home movies
    16mm and 35mm home movies and travelogues created from the 1920s to the 1960s. The 35mm films are copies, probably made in the 1940s, from hazardous (flammable) nitrate stock.
    - Palm Beach House, 1920s (Box AV-19, Film-reel RL01167-F35-0005)
    - Bear Hunt and Fishing, circa 1920s (Box AV-20, Film-reel RL01167-F35-0009)
    - Tennis and Horseback, circa 1920s (Box AV-20, Film-reel RL01167-F35-0010)
    - Boxing in the Woods, circa 1920s (Box AV-20, Film-reel RL01167-F35-0011)
    - Mary's Birthday and Nick Playing Tennis, "Sweetest Story", circa 1920s (Box AV-20, Film-reel RL01167-F35-0012)
    - The Boat, Palm Beach Bath and Tennis Club, circa 1920s (Box AV-20, Film-reel RL01167-F35-0013)
    - Linden Courts, tennis fights and children, 1923-1924 (Box AV-19, Film-reel RL01167-F35-0006)
    - Palm Beach 1924 (Box AV-18, Film-reel RL01167-F35-0002)
    - Palm Beach - children, circa 1924 (Box AV-18, Film-reel RL01167-F35-0003)
    - Grandma Duke, circa 1924 (Box AV-19, Film-reel RL01167-F35-0004)
    - Tony's Automobile, Tony's Birthday, 1929; Newport, 1925; Palm Beach, 1926, 1925-1929 (Box AV-18, Film-reel RL01167-F35-0001)
    - Summer of 1926 - Newport R.I. Aspen Hall (Box AV-19, Film-reel RL01167-F35-0007)
    - A Day with the Biddles, Palm Beach, 1926 (Box AV-19, Film-reel RL01167-F35-0008)
    - Parade 1931 Le Touquet France (Box AV-13, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0030)
    - Joe Trent and Mary, 1939, Irvington and Ranch (Box AV-13, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0028)
    - Home movies, 1930 and 1940s, 1930s-1940s (Box AV-13, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0032)
    - Home movies, 1940s (Box AV-13, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0029)
    - 1954-1957 family movies, spring (Box AV-14, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0027)
    - Family European Trip, 1958 (Box AV-14, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0036)
    - Home movies, 1960s (Box AV-13, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0033)
    - Duke and children, Irvington, old family film, Mary and Uncle Nick, Joe Stuart, Nick, and Mary, undated (Box AV-13, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0026)
    - Home movies, undated (Box AV-13, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0034)
    - Home movies, undated (Box AV-13, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0035)
  - Commercial releases
    16mm commercial releases purchased for home viewing. Of particular note is a full print of Jean Renoir's Lower Depths (1936), as well as two reels of highlights from the 1936 Olympics.
    - Hits From the Past [Charlie Chaplin - The Property Man (1914)] (Box AV-1, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0018)
    - The Rink, 1916 (Box AV-1, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0024)
    - The Adventurer, 1917 (Box AV-1, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0023)
    - Cocoanuts (Marx Bros.), reel 1, 1929 (Box AV-1, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0031)
    - Merry Christmas, 1930s (Box AV-1, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0009)
    - The Cuckoo Murder Case, 1930 (Box AV-1, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0006)
    - The Dentist, 1932 (Box AV-1, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0019)
    - Tight Rope Tricks, 1933 (Box AV-1, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0013)
    - Three Little Kittens, 1933 (Box AV-1, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0014)
    - Big Bad Wolf, 1934 (Box AV-1, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0001)
    - Farm Frolics, 1934 (Box AV-1, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0016)
    - Puss In Boots, 1934 (Box AV-1, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0017)
    - Mary's Little Lamb, 1934 (Box AV-1, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0021)
    - Jack Frost, 1934 (Box AV-1, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0022)
    - Cactus Capers, 1934 (Box AV-1, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0025)
    - Robinson Crusoe Mickey, 1935 (Box AV-1, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0002)
    - Old Mother Hubbard, 1935 (Box AV-2, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0003)
    - Zoo's Who!, 1935 (Box AV-2, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0007)
    - Dick Wittington's Cat, 1936 (Box AV-2, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0012)
    - Lower Depths (Jean Renoir, 1936), Reel 2 (Box AV-2, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0037)
    - Lower Depths (Jean Renoir, 1936), Reel 1 (Box AV-2, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0038)
    - The Live and Loves of Beethoven (Abel Gance, 1936), Reel 1 (Box AV-2, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0039)
    - The Live and Loves of Beethoven (Abel Gance, 1936), Reel 2 (Box AV-2, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0040)
    - 1936 Olympics highlights (Box AV-2, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0041)
    - 1936 Olympics highlights (Box AV-2, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0042)
    - The News Parade of the Year: 1938, 1939 (Box AV-2, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0020)
    - The News Parade of the Year: 1939, 1940 (Box AV-2, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0015)
    - All This and Rabbit Stew, 1941 (Box AV-2, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0004)
    - All This and Rabbit Stew, 1941 (Box AV-2, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0005)
    - Woody Woodpecker, 1941 (Box AV-2, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0008)
    - The News Parade of the Year: 1940, 1941 (Box AV-2, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0011)
    - The News Parade: Victory Over Germany, 1945 (Box AV-2, Film-reel RL01167-F16-0010)
  - Video
    Two-inch open reel quad video of a concert in Siena, Italy, in 1968, likely related to the Semans' work with the North Carolina School of the Arts and its Siena summer session. The video was produced by WNDT/Channel 13, New York (now known as WNET 13).
    - Siena Concert, 1968-03-03 (Box AV-17, Video-reel RL01167-Vid2-0001)
- Additions
  (Acc. 2016-0121; Acc. 2016-0131) Contains additions to the collection received by the library in 2016, in the form of family photographs and photograph albums. Images range in date from the early 1900s to the 1990s. Glass plate negatives are open to use only with permission of curator.
  - Assorted family photographs, 13 folders (Box Acc. 16/0131: Box 1)
  - Assorted family photographs, 23 folders (Box Acc. 16/0131: Box 2)
  - Assorted family photographs, 14 folders (Box Acc. 16/0131: Box 3)
  - Family photograph albums, 3 items (Box Acc. 16/0131: Box 3)
  - Family photograph albums, 9 items (Box Acc. 16/0131: Box 4)
  - Family photograph albums, 9 items (Box Acc. 16/0131: Box 5)
  - Oversize family photographs, 2 folders (Box Acc. 16/0131: Box 6)
  - Oversize family photographs, 1 folders (Box Acc. 16/0131: Box 7)
  - Family photograph album (Box Acc. 16/0131: Box 8)
  - Slides (Box Acc. 16/0131: Box 9)
  - Slides (Box Acc. 16/0131: Box 10)
    Contains glass plate negatives.
    Glass plate negatives are open to use only with permission by curator. Please contact the Rubenstein Library before coming to use these materials.